{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The key enzyme in the regulation of fatty acid synthesis is", "opta": "acetyl CoA carboxylase", "optb": "AMP activated proteinkinase", "optc": "protein phosphatase", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Arachidonate has 20 carbon atoms with", "opta": "3 double bonds", "optb": "2 double bonds", "optc": "4 double bonds", "optd": "8 double bonds", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the intestine, the dietary fats are hydrolysed by", "opta": "triacylglycerol lipase", "optb": "adenylate cyclase", "optc": "pancreatic lipase", "optd": "protein kinase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "HDLs are synthesized in", "opta": "blood", "optb": "liver", "optc": "intestine", "optd": "pancreas", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Triacylglycerols are", "opta": "soluble in water", "optb": "insoluble in water", "optc": "soluble in water at elevated temperature", "optd": "partially soluble in water", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Animals cannot convert fatty acids into glucose because", "opta": "acetyl CoA can not be converted to pyruvate", "optb": "absence of  malate synthase", "optc": "absence of dehydrogenase", "optd": "absence of a-ketoglutarate dehydrogenase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In eukaryotes fatty acid breakdown occurs in", "opta": "mitochondrial matrix", "optb": "cytosol", "optc": "cell membrane", "optd": "endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the major protein constituent of high-density lipoprotein (HDL)?", "opta": "Apolipoprotein A-l", "optb": "Apolipoprotein C-l", "optc": "Apolipoprotein E", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phospholipid contains", "opta": "hydrophilic heads and hydrophobic tails", "optb": "long water-soluble carbon chains", "optc": "positively charged functional groups", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Micelles of fatty acids in water are organized such that the __________ faces the solvent and the __________ are directed toward the interior", "opta": "carboxylic acid groups, hydrocarbon chains heads", "optb": "hydrophilic heads, hydrophobic tails", "optc": "hydrocarbon chains, carboxylic acid groups", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cholesterolemia means", "opta": "lack of functional LDL receptors", "optb": "lack of functional HDL receptor", "optc": "high sensitivity to fatty food intake", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fatty acids break down of eukaryotes occurs in", "opta": "mitochondrial matrix", "optb": "cell membrane", "optc": "cytosol", "optd": "endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "VLDLs are synthesized in", "opta": "blood", "optb": "liver", "optc": "intestine", "optd": "pancreas", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chylomicrons are synthesized in", "opta": "blood", "optb": "liver", "optc": "intestine", "optd": "pancreas", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many types of lipoproteins are there?", "opta": "2", "optb": "6", "optc": "8", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fatty acid synthesis takes place in", "opta": "mitochondria", "optb": "cell membrane", "optc": "cytosol", "optd": "endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cholestrol is the precursor of", "opta": "steroid hormones", "optb": "vitamin A", "optc": "bile salts", "optd": "both (a) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Atherosclerosis can cause blood", "opta": "thinning", "optb": "clotting", "optc": "thickening", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Palmitate has 16 carbon atoms with", "opta": "2 double bonds", "optb": "3 double bonds", "optc": "One double bond", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many ATPs are formed during complete oxidation of palmitate?", "opta": "35", "optb": "96", "optc": "129", "optd": "131", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lowest energy value lipid for human nutrition is", "opta": "olive oil", "optb": "olestra", "optc": "margarine", "optd": "cardiolipih", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many classes of steroid hormones are there?", "opta": "3", "optb": "2", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of water molecules consumed by the formation of phosphatidyl serine are", "opta": "0", "optb": "1", "optc": "2", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synthesis of fatty acid takes place when", "opta": "fatty acid are plentiful", "optb": "carbohydrate is plentiful", "optc": "carbohydrate and energy are plentiful", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is called milk ejection hormone?", "opta": "Prolactin", "optb": "Vasopressin", "optc": "Oxytocin", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}